

## **ABOUT ME**

Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt &

Lean Six Sigma Green Belt:

I am well versed in the core to advanced elements of Lean Six Sigma Methodology, I am capable of leading improvement projects and / or serve as a team member as a part of more complex improvement projects. I am able implement, perform, interpret and apply Lean Six Sigma at a high level of proficiency. Minimize expenditure- Maximize profit.

## CONTACT



wallaceremonia@gmail.com

## **INTERESTS**

Philosophy

Reading

**Problem Solving** 

Art (Various Forms)

Physical Activities

Meditation

## **SKILLS**

Attentive listening and effective oral communication skills

••••

Critical Thinker

•••••

Good Leadership Skills

•••••

Great at Problem Solving

00000

# Remonia Wallace

**Laboratory Supervisor-Biochemist** 

## CAREER OBJECTIVE

To obtain a leadership role in the Biochemical industry focused on incorporating and applying my industry safety, scientific and biopharmaceutical knowledge to the fast-expanding field. In addition to, providing laboratory development and growth consultations for new cannabis extraction labs.

## **EDUCATION**

#### **BACHELOR DEGREE-2016**

Bachelor of Science in Forensic Science & Chemistry Minor Long Island University-Post Certifications: American Chemical Society (ACS) Chemist Lean Six Sigma Yellow Belt Certified

#### **HIGHLIGHTS**

GPA: 3.55 Member  $\Phi H \Sigma$  National Honors Society

# TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES:

Supercritical CO<sub>2</sub> fluid cannabinoid extraction, Ethanol extraction, Soxhlet extraction, Polymer formulation, Biochemical Instrumentation; Column chromatography, HPLC, GCMS, FTIR, ICP OES, Microwave Digestion, XRF Fluorescence, Hydrogen NMR, UV-Vis spectroscopy Biochemical Research and lab documentation Computer / Software skills: Microsoft office (word, excel, power-point, access, publisher,

Teamwork and Verbal Communication

## **EXPERIENCE**

### LABORATORY SUPERVISOR-HPLC

05/2021 to Present | Charles River Laboratories

• Oversee daily operational activities within the laboratory. Schedule and prioritize workload of assigned group. Ensure optimum group performance. Recommend short-range operating objectives, organizational structure, staffing requirements and succession plans. Serve as a model to departmental subordinates as it relates to effective time management, communication and utilization of resources.

etc.) expert.

- Provide direct daily supervision and review work of assigned departmental employees to ensure accuracy and adherence to GMP standards, laboratory SOPs, safety procedures and protocols. Assist in the interview and selection of qualified non-exempt personnel. Monitor performance of direct reports. Assist in providing regular direction, coaching and counseling.
- Assist in developing recommendations regarding personnel actions, including hiring, promotions and raises.
- Assist in preparation and delivery of salary and performance reviews of direct reports.
- Partner with Human Resources and departmental management to assist in the handling of disciplinary issues. Assist in the drafting of appropriate personnel action paperwork.
- Create, review and edit SOPs, protocols and other data Forms and testing documentation.

## RESEARCH ASSOCIATE II

## 12/2020 to 05/2021 | Charles River Laboratories

- Perform compendial/non-compendial and complex analytical methods, data interpretation and reporting independently as specified in standard in-house SOPs, Client Test Methods and other written procedures.
- Independently perform and assist scientific staff with client-specific experimental design, moderately complex professional tasks, report development, quality control, and research. These may include method feasibility, development, optimization, transfers, qualifications, validations and for conducting routine testing under both R&D and cGMP environments.
- Responsible for client interaction, interpretation and reporting of data for assigned research projects

#### EXTRACTION MANAGER, PRODUCTION MANAGER & FORMULATION CHEMIST

03/2020 to 08/2020|Tonic CBD & Bardo Labs

- Lean process standardization and SOP preparation
- Ensure that Tonic CBD's manufacturing process runs reliably and efficiently, manage process improvements, maintain product quality and integrity, organize production workflow to meet specifications and deadlines.
- Maintains product quality and consistency according to CGMP guidelines. Responsible for controlling the quality of the work performed and any final products sold. Perform physiochemical investigations of CBD products.
- Manage and maintain the Bardo extraction process, have adept knowledge of supercritical CO<sub>2</sub> and ethanol extraction methods as well as the purification, separation and isolation of various cannabinoids
- Ensured the safe, accurate, and timely production of CBD distillate and maintained cleanliness of laboratory

## ASSOCIATE PROJECT CHEMIST

09/2017 to 03/2020 | Underwriters Laboratories (UL)

- Manage execution and timely completion of engineering projects by analyzing project scope and determining project specifications
- Establish test programs for product investigations,
- Analyze test programs for adequacy and sequence, examining samples for compliance with UL requirements, and preparing reports for clients.